Danny Kaye and Sylvia Fine Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Other (Box 1-3, 2-A, 4-A--93-A, 95-A--131-A, 133-A--184-A, 36-B, 45-C, 80-B, 80-C, 102-B, OV 1-OV 25, OV 27-OV 33, OV 866)
  - Miscellaneous Materials
    - Books
      - Lauritzen, Philip. Grønland på vingerne (Box 172-A)
      - Lytle, Clyde Francis (edited by). Leaves of Gold, (gift from Nancy Borchet) (Box 172-A)
      - McKeldin, Theodore. No Mean City, (autographed by author) (Box 172-A)
      - Pederson, Kenno and Lars Bjørn Madsen. Det gamle Nordsjælland (Box 172-A)
      - Pendlesonn, KRG. The Vikings, (gift and letter from Eva Bredsdorff, 1983 ) (Box 172-A)
      - Rowe, Percey. Golden Leaves from Canada's Past 1867-1967 (Box 172-A)
      - Schneekloth, Ida. Et barn er født, (autographed by author with a note) (Box 172-A)
      - Pitkänen, Matti A. Suomi, (gift and photograph from Tiina Tavistie, 1983) (Box 172-A)
    - Magazines
      - The American Home, "At Home With Danny Kaye," November, 1960 (Box 80-B)
      - The Kiwanis, "Danny Kaye: The Man For All Seasons," November, 1974 (Box 80-B)
      - McCalls, "The Danny Kaye Picture Book," January, 1958 (photocopy) (Box 80-B)
      - Omni, April, 1982 (Box 80-B)
    - Realia
      - Ashtray (United States Senate) (Box 74-A)
      - Baseballs (Four encased souvenir balls from 1977 Inaugural Game, Seattle Mariners vs. California Angels) (Box 108-A)
      - Baton (engraved "Gadna Orchestra International Tour" 1967 ) (Box 164-A)
      - Briefcase (personalized Samsonite) (Box OV 4)
      - Children's artwork, cards and letters to Danny Kaye (UNICEF-related) (Box OV 866)
      - City of Norfolk (Norfolk's Historic Mace) (Box 164-A)
      - Clapboard (Polavision, 1978 ) (Box 44-A)
      - Clay jug (Box 2-A)
      - Clock (Israel Watch Co.) (Box 84-A)
      - Crown in wooden case (Box OV 1)
      - Cuff links (Box 131-A)
      - Dies, Colonial Theatre advertisement for Danny Kaye appearance "With many thanks, Danny Kaye" (2) (Box 39-A)
      - Flags, miniature (3) (Box 123-A)
      - Goblets, silver engraved (3) (Box 107-A)
      - Hats
        - Cap (white with USO emblem) (Box 73-A)
        - Helmet (personalized) (Box OV 5)
        - Mine Safety hat (personalized; contains emblems; autographed by supplier) (Box OV 6)
        - Velvet (black) (Box 73-A)
      - Horseshoes (3) (Box 15-A)
      - Key chains (3) (Box 39-A)
      - Keys to cities, miniature (9) (Box 123-A)
      - Knives (2) (Box 101-A)
      - Medals and Medallions
        - Memphis Chamber of Commerce, Memphis, Tennessee (medal) (Box 18-A)
        - New Orleans Mardi Gras Float Lieutenant medallion (Box 41-A)
        - Sted. Carnaval medallion, 1971 (Box 41-A)
        - United Nations Childrens' Funds (UNICEF) March medals in case (4) (Box 41-A)
        - Miscellaneous medals (25) (Box 105-A, 106-A)
      - Model airplanes
        - Boeing 737 set on personalized engraved wooden base (Box 17-A)
        - Plane made out of nails, screws and wire (Box OV 3)
      - Mugs (2) (Box 14-A)
      - Music Box (one gallon paint can with "Happiness" on covering and dedication) (Box 114-A)
      - Paperweights
        - Camp Fire Girls (Box 44-A)
        - City of Buffalo
          - Glass - 1963 (Box 44-A)
          - Buffalo statue (Box 44-A)
        - San Antonio, Texas (Box 44-A)
      - Parachute (Box *)
      - Patches (14) (Box 123-A)
      - Pen holder ("Okinawa - 1967 ") (Box 41-A)
      - Pins (11) (Box 123-A)
      - Placements (4 papercuts by Hans Christian Andersen) (Box 91-A)
      - Plaques
        - Danny Kaye
          - 313th Air Division (Box 26-A)
          - The American Film Institute, "A Salute to John Ford," 1973 (Box 9-A)
          - Congressional Record, November 30, 1967 (Box 62-A)
          - Cue, cover, "Danny Kaye, Entertainer of the Year," January, 1971 (Box 62-A)
          - Dodger Stadium Olympic Baseball, Los Angeles, 1984 (Box 108-A)
          - DK, Danmark (Box 38-A)
          - Flight Safety, Inc., 1970 (Box 45-C)
          - Jewish engraving (2), 1967 (Box 37-A, 57-A)
          - Letter from Ronald Reagan, 1982 (Box 76-A)
          - Los Angeles Times, "Walter Mitty leads the Philharmonic," February 5, 1973 (Box 171-A)
          - Love (gift given by M r. & Mrs. M.C. Jones) (Box 38-A)
          - Newsweek, "Danny Kaye at the Met," January, 1973 (Box 147-A)
          - Photograph (Box 38-A)
          - RKO Palace Theatre (caricature of Danny Kaye; autographed by P.S. 149 Gang) (Box 38-A)
          - South African Tour, May, 1954 (Box 165-A)
          - Telegrams
            - Peter Omalley, 1982 (Box 76-A)
            - Pierre Elliot Trudeau, Prime Minister of Canada, 1981 (Box 76-A)
          - Tiger's Milk (includes photo of Danny Kaye with Jim and Art Ingoldsby with their autograph) (Box 147-A)
          - TV guide cover
            - February 1-7, "Danny Kaye and Laurie Ichino" (Box 26-A)
            - Oct.29-Nov.4, "Danny Kaye in a special this week" (Box 26-A)
          - UNICEF (engraving) (Box 173-A)
        - Sylvia Fine
          - The American Film Institute, "A salute to John Ford," 1973 (Box 9-A)
          - Best Original Song in a Motion Picture 1959, The Five Pennies (Box 112-A)
          - Best Original Song Score for a Motion Picture 1959, The Five Pennies (Box 112-A)
      - Plate (commemorative London Palladium, 1949 ) (Box 74-A)
      - Platters
        - 2nd Battle Group 3rd Infantry (Korea Christmas 1961 with correspondence, photograph, and calendar) (Box 85-A)
        - Hans Christian Andersen, copper engraved, autographed, 1972 (Box 91-A)
        - Royal Holland Pewter (Box 91-A)
      - Posters
        - Israel, Gordon & Barbara (Box 172-A)
      - Robes
        - Pomona College, Claremont, California, 1978 (with correspondence and program) (Box 80-C)
        - Miscellaneous robe (1) (Box 79-A)
        - Miscellaneous college robes (7) (Box 174-A)
      - Scrolls
        - Caesars Palace, Las Vegas, Nevada (Box 173-A)
      - Silver trays (engraved)
        - Danny Kaye
          - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1964 (Box 87-A)
          - The Rhuallan Club, 1949 (Box 87-A)
          - The Sick Benefit Club of Odense, 1952 (Box 87-A)
          - The Theatre Royal Dublin, 1952 (Box 87-A)
          - University of Southern California, 1970 (Box 87-A)
        - Sylvia Fine
          - University of Southern California, 1973 (Box 87-A)
      - Souvenirs
        - Korean (5) (Box 110-A)
        - Miscellaneous souvenirs(21) (Box 113-A)
      - Statues
        - Head sculpture of Danny Kaye (Box OV 29)
        - Montreal Symphony Orchestra, 1983
          - "Man with Whip" (Box OV 27)
          - "Man holding Paddle" (broken) (Box OV 28)
        - The Toronto Symphony, 1966 (Box OV 24)
        - Wooden replica of Danny Kaye mounted with engraving (Box OV 25)
      - Swords (2) (Box OV 25)
      - Tapestry (Box 173-A)
      - Trophies (3) (Box 82-A)
      - Whip (Box 80-A)
      - Whistle (Box 123-A)
      - Wooden Momentos
        - Airplane (Box 101-A)
        - Arrows (6) (Box 85-A)
        - Black leather shoes, 1949 (Box 104-A)
        - Carvings (2) (Box 77-A, 101-A)
        - Case with engraved silver tree, 1984 (Box 131-A)
        - Dutch clogs (Box OV 32)
        - Key (Box 39-A)
        - Key signature stick (Box 39-A)
        - Name plate "Danny Kaye" (Box 173-A)
        - "Noah's Ark" (Box 131-A)
        - Red River Cart (Box OV 31)
        - Sculpture of outline of the Statue of Liberty with engraving and CBS logo for "An American Portrait" (Box 18-A)
        - Sheep (Box OV 2)
        - Statues (3) (Box OV 12-13)
        - Stick (Box 101-A)